Hello, English learners.
你好，英语学习者。
Welcome back to EnglishPod.
欢迎回到EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我叫Marco。
And I'm Erika.
我是Erika。
And today we're bringing you another great lesson about sports, part of our sports series.
今天我们要给你们带来另一节关于体育的精彩课程，这是我们体育系列的一部分。
That's right.
没错。
And in this lesson, we are talking about maybe the world's most favorite sport.
在这节课中，我们要谈论的可能是全世界最受欢迎的体育运动。
Right.
对。
One of the most popular sports in the world, soccer.
世界上最受欢迎的运动之一，足球。
Or also known as football in other countries.
在其他国家也被称为football。
Yes.
是的。
So, before we get started with this great lesson, let's take a look at some of the words
那么，在我们开始这节精彩的课程之前，让我们先看一下词汇预览中对话里会出现的一些单词。
we'll find in the dialogue in Vocabulary Preview.
词汇预览。
Vocabulary Preview.
We're going to look at three words here.
我们要看三个词。
The first word is wingman.
第一个词是wingman。
Wingman.
Wingman。
A wingman.
一个wingman。
Now, wingman isn't really related to soccer in any way.
嗯，wingman其实和足球没什么关系。
Okay.
好的。
But it's a way of referring to somebody as your right hand.
但它是一种称呼某人为你得力助手的方式。
So your helper.
也就是你的帮手。
Your helper.
你的帮手。
Your number one guy.
你的头号人物。
Okay.
好的。
Right.
对。
So a wingman is someone who helps you a lot.
所以wingman就是那个帮你很多忙的人。
Exactly.
没错。
Okay.
好的。
Our next word, tied.
下一个词，tied。
Tied.
Tied。
They are tied.
他们打平了。
Now, this is an interesting word because tie can be a noun, verb, and an adjective, right?
这个词很有意思，因为tie可以是名词、动词，还有形容词，对吧？
Exactly.
没错。
So in this case, they are tied.
所以在这里，they are tied。
It's an adjective meaning...
它是一个形容词，意思是……
They have the same score.
他们得分相同。
Okay.
好的。
So a tie is...
所以tie就是……
Is a game that has ended with no winner or loser.
一场没有赢家或输家的比赛。
Both of them had the same score.
双方得分相同。
Exactly.
没错。
And so obviously, the verb to tie is to reach the same score as your other team.
那么很明显，动词to tie就是和对方球队达到相同得分。
Exactly.
没错。
All right.
好的。
Well, our third word can also be used as a noun and a verb and it is foul.
嗯，我们的第三个词也可以用作名词和动词，它就是foul。
Fouled.
Fouled。
Okay.
好的。
So, to foul somebody is to do something to them that is not allowed in the sport.
所以，to foul somebody就是在运动中对他们做不被允许的事情。
Okay.
好的。
And so when you do this, you have committed a foul.
当你这样做时，你就犯了一个foul（犯规）。
Exactly.
没错。
Okay.
好的。
So you use it in the same way, to foul or a foul.
所以用法是一样的，to foul或a foul。
Interesting.
有意思。
Well, we're going to hear these three words in context now.
嗯，我们现在要在上下文中听到这三个词了。
So why don't we listen to our soccer dialogue?
那我们为什么不听听我们的足球对话呢？
Welcome back, soccer fans.
欢迎回来，球迷们。
My name is Rick Fields.
我是Rick Fields。
And as always, I am joined by my commentating wingman, Bob Copeland.
和往常一样，我的解说搭档Bob Copeland也在这里。
And we're in the brink of soccer history today as Ecuador and Brazil are tied 1-1.
今天我们正处在足球历史的边缘，厄瓜多尔和巴西1-1打平。
As we begin the second half of the 2022 World Cup.
2022年世界杯下半场开始了。
The ref calls the players for the kickoff.
裁判叫球员们准备开球。
And here we go.
比赛开始了。
Ecuador quickly passes the ball to the midfield.
厄瓜多尔迅速将球传到中场。
But oh, it's out of bounds.
但是哦，球出界了。
That'll be a throw in for Brazil.
巴西队获得一个界外球。
Adriano has the ball and makes a long pass to Robinho.
Adriano拿到球，长传给Robinho。
And the ref has called him offside.
裁判判他越位。
No question about it.
毫无疑问。
He was offside by a mile.
他越位了一大截。
We have a goal kick for Ecuador.
厄瓜多尔队获得一个球门球。
Edison Mendes heads it to Valencia.
Edison Mendes头球传给Valencia。
He shoots.
他射门了。
Deflected by the defender.
被后卫挡出。
And we have a corner kick.
我们得到一个角球。
Delgado takes the corner.
Delgado主罚角球。
We have a foul.
犯规了。
Oh no.
哦不。
Dida, the goalkeeper, has fouled the Ecuadorian player.
守门员Dida对厄瓜多尔球员犯规了。
He gets a yellow card.
他得到一张黄牌。
And that will be a penalty kick.
那将是一个点球。
This is the perfect opportunity for Ecuador to get ahead in this match and become world
这是厄瓜多尔在这场比赛中取得领先并成为世界冠军的绝佳机会。
champions.
冠军。
He gets ready for the kick.
他准备罚球。
He shoots.
他射门了。
And he...
他……
OK, so Ecuador tied with Brazil in the 2022 World Cup.
好的，所以厄瓜多尔在2022年世界杯上与巴西打平了。
Wow, Marco, I'm really happy to see that you are able to see so far into the future.
哇，Marco，我很高兴看到你能预见那么远的未来。
Well, I called it.
嗯，我早就说过了。
So in 2022, if we do win the World Cup, you know who said it first.
所以到2022年，如果我们真的赢了世界杯，你知道是谁先说的。
All right.
好的。
Do you have money on that?
你押注了吗？
Yes.
是的。
All right.
好的。
So apart from this, we saw some really great vocabulary in this lesson.
除了这个，我们在这节课中还看到了一些很棒的词汇。
So let's take a look at it now in Language Takeaway.
那我们现在在语言要点部分来看看它们。
Language Takeaway.
语言要点。
All right.
好的。
We've got a lot of soccer words for you, but they're all important.
我们为你准备了很多足球词汇，但它们都很重要。
So let's take a look at the first one.
那我们来看看第一个。
Kick off.
Kick off。
So a kick off.
所以kick off。
This is how you start a soccer game, right?
这是足球比赛开始的方式，对吧？
Right.
对。
So in the beginning, the referee blows the whistle and you kick the ball to another player.
所以一开始，裁判吹哨，你把球踢给另一个球员。
That's the kick off.
那就是开球。
OK.
好的。
So our next phrase, out of bounds.
下一个短语，out of bounds。
Out of bounds.
Out of bounds。
OK.
好的。
Out of bounds.
Out of bounds。
This is a great word.
这个词很棒。
So in soccer, when the ball goes out of bounds, it goes outside the white lines, right?
在足球中，当球出界时，它跑到白线外面了，对吧？
Right.
对。
Outside of the playing field.
比赛场地之外。
OK.
好的。
And you can use it in all other sports.
你可以在所有其他运动中使用它。
You can use it in basketball.
你可以在篮球中使用它。
You can use it in tennis.
你可以在网球中使用它。
Or football or anything.
或者橄榄球或其他任何运动。
Right.
对。
So any part that is not for playing.
所以任何非比赛区域。
Out of bounds.
Out of bounds。
What's our next word?
下一个词是什么？
Throw in.
Throw in。
A throw in.
一个throw in。
OK.
好的。
So a throw in.
所以throw in。
The ball goes out of bounds.
球出界了。
How do you put it back into play?
你怎么把它重新投入比赛？
Obviously, a throw in.
很明显，一个界外球。
OK.
好的。
So you throw in the ball.
所以你把球扔进来。
That's the only time where a soccer player will actually grab the ball with his hands.
这是足球运动员唯一一次用手拿球。
All right.
好的。
Now, another soccer term we have here, offside.
现在，我们还有另一个足球术语，offside。
Offside.
Offside。
OK.
好的。
So this is a little bit difficult to explain.
这个有点难解释。
But just imagine you're on the soccer field.
但想象一下你在足球场上。
And you are trying to score a goal.
你试图进球。
Now, you have some defenders, right?
现在，你有一些后卫，对吧？
Right.
对。
Those are the people who are trying to take the ball away.
那些是试图抢走球的人。
And you pass the ball to somebody who is behind the defenders.
你把球传给一个在后卫后面的人。
Oh, and that person is offside.
哦，那个人就越位了。
Exactly.
没错。
So, you must be at all times in the same position as the defenders or in front of them.
所以，你必须始终与后卫处于同一位置或在他们前面。
But you can't be all the way in the back.
但不能一直跑到后面。
OK.
好的。
So is this a noun or a verb or an adjective?
那这是名词、动词还是形容词？
So this is an adjective.
这是形容词。
He is offside.
他越位了。
That's his condition.
那是他的状态。
OK.
好的。
Great.
很好。
Excellent explanation, Marco.
解释得很棒，Marco。
Thank you.
谢谢。
All right.
好的。
Now, we're going to look at three different phrases for three types of kicks in soccer.
现在，我们要看三个关于足球中三种踢球方式的短语。
OK.
好的。
So let's take a look at this.
那我们来看看这个。
The first one is goal kick.
第一个是goal kick。
A goal kick.
一个goal kick。
OK.
好的。
Goal kick.
Goal kick。
So who does the goal kick?
谁踢球门球？
It's usually the goalie or the goalkeeper who takes the goal kick.
通常是守门员或门将来踢球门球。
OK.
好的。
So when the goalie kicks the ball.
所以当门将踢球时。
Mm-hmm.
嗯哼。
Now, what about a corner kick?
那corner kick呢？
OK.
好的。
So if the team is attacking and the ball goes out of bounds in the back area near the goal,
如果进攻方把球踢到靠近球门的后场区域出界了，那么他们得到一个角球。
then they get a corner kick.
他们必须从球场的角落踢球。
They've got to kick the ball from the corner of the field.
这是一个进球的好机会，对吧？
This is a great chance to score a goal, isn't it?
没错。
Exactly.
是的。
Yes.
好的。
OK.
那penalty kick呢？
And what about a penalty kick?
Penalty kick。
Penalty kick.
So if a player gets fouled while he is in the area near the goal, he gets a penalty
如果一名球员在靠近球门的区域被犯规，他得到一个点球。
kick.
所以基本上，只有他一个人。
So basically, it's just him.
我想离门将大概13或15步远，他有机会进球或踢球。
I think it's 13 or 15 steps away from the goalie and he gets the opportunity to score
所以没有后卫或其他球员挡路。
or to kick the ball.
没有人。
So there are no defenders or other players in the way.
哇。
Nobody.
另一个进球的好机会。
Wow.
对。
Another great chance to score a goal.
好的。
Right.
对。
All right.
好的。
Well, these are all great soccer words.
嗯，这些都是很棒的足球词汇。
I think we should hear them again in context.
我觉得我们应该在语境中再听一遍。
So let's listen this time a little bit slower.
所以这次我们慢一点听。
Welcome back, soccer fans.
欢迎回来，球迷们。
My name is Rick Fields.
我是里克·菲尔兹。
And as always, I am joined by my commentating wingman, Bob Copeland.
和往常一样，我的解说搭档鲍勃·科普兰也在这里。
And we're on the brink of soccer history today as Ecuador and Brazil are tied 1-1 as we begin
今天我们正处在足球历史的边缘，厄瓜多尔和巴西以1-1战平，
the second half of the 2022 World Cup.
2022年世界杯下半场开始了。
The ref calls the players for the kickoff.
裁判召集球员准备开球。
And here we go.
我们开始了。
Ecuador quickly passes the ball to the midfield.
厄瓜多尔迅速将球传到中场。
But oh, it's out of bounds.
但哦，球出界了。
That will be a throw in for Brazil.
巴西将获得一个界外球。
Adriano has the ball and makes a long pass to Rubinho.
阿德里亚诺拿球，长传给鲁比尼奥。
And the ref has called him offside.
裁判判他越位。
No question about it.
毫无疑问。
He was offside by a mile.
他越位了一大截。
We have a goal kick for Ecuador.
厄瓜多尔获得一个球门球。
Edison Mendez heads it to Valencia.
埃迪森·门德斯头球传给瓦伦西亚。
He shoots.
他射门了。
Deflected by the defender.
被后卫挡出。
And we have a corner kick.
我们获得一个角球。
Delgado takes the corner.
德尔加多主罚角球。
We have a foul.
犯规了。
Oh, no.
哦，不。
Dida, the goalkeeper, has fouled the Ecuadorian player.
门将迪达对厄瓜多尔球员犯规了。
He gets a yellow card.
他吃到一张黄牌。
And that will be a penalty kick.
那将是一个点球。
This is the perfect opportunity for Ecuador to get ahead in this match and become world
这是厄瓜多尔在这场比赛中领先并成为世界冠军的绝佳机会。
champions.
冠军。
He gets ready for the kick.
他准备罚球。
He shoots.
他射门了。
And he...
他……
All right.
好的。
So we heard these words that we were talking about in context.
所以我们在语境中听到了这些我们讨论过的词。
And now, some really interesting phrases came up.
现在，出现了一些非常有趣的短语。
And this would be a good time to take a look at them in Fluency Builder.
现在是时候在流利度提升环节看看它们了。
Fluency Builder.
流利度提升。
Well, Marco, there are three great phrases in this dialogue that I want to look at.
嗯，马可，这段对话中有三个很棒的短语我想看看。
The first one, on the brink of.
第一个是“on the brink of”。
We are on the brink of.
我们正处在……的边缘。
We're on the brink of soccer history.
我们正处在足球历史的边缘。
Okay.
好的。
So, on the brink of.
所以，“on the brink of”。
What exactly does that mean?
这到底是什么意思？
Well, why don't we hear some examples to help us understand the meaning.
嗯，我们不如听一些例子来帮助理解它的意思。
Example one.
例子一。
Look, we don't have any money.
看，我们没钱了。
We're on the brink of going bankrupt.
我们濒临破产。
Example two.
例子二。
The two countries are on the brink of war.
这两个国家处于战争边缘。
Example three.
例子三。
We're on the brink of an important discovery.
我们即将取得一项重要发现。
All right.
好的。
So great examples, on the brink of, at a critical point.
很好的例子，“on the brink of”意思是处于关键点。
Exactly.
没错。
It means you're almost there, right?
它意味着你几乎要到了，对吧？
Okay.
好的。
Yeah.
是的。
Very good.
非常好。
And what about this next phrase that I saw and it was really interesting.
那下一个短语呢？我看到了，觉得很有趣。
No question about it.
“No question about it”。
毫无疑问。
No question about it.
All right.
好的。
So, this is a statement that doesn't really make much sense.
所以，这个说法听起来不太有道理。
But what am I saying when I say, oh, no question about it?
但我说“哦，毫无疑问”时，我在表达什么？
You're saying, I agree.
你在说，我同意。
There is no doubt.
没有疑问。
You're right.
你说得对。
Okay.
好的。
Well, let's give some examples.
嗯，我们举些例子。
I could say, there's no question about it.
我可以说，毫无疑问。
Ecuador is a great soccer team.
厄瓜多尔是一支很棒的足球队。
There is no question about that.
这一点毫无疑问。
All right.
好的。
So, or you can say, no question about it.
所以，或者你可以说，毫无疑问。
Our company makes the best products on the market.
我们公司生产市场上最好的产品。
Okay.
好的。
So, really useful phrase that you can use in sports or anywhere else.
所以，这是一个非常有用的短语，可以在体育或其他任何场合使用。
Okay.
好的。
And now let's take a look at our last phrase for Fluency Builder.
现在让我们看看流利度提升环节的最后一个短语。
And it's a really good one to exaggerate a little bit.
这是一个很好的用来稍微夸张的短语。
Okay.
好的。
By a mile.
“By a mile”。
差了一大截。
By a mile.
So, he was offside by a mile.
所以，他越位了一大截。
Right.
对。
So, the commentator is saying that he was very offside.
所以，解说员在说他越位得很明显。
That it was really obvious.
非常明显。
Right.
对。
So, you can use that also in different contexts, maybe not in sports.
所以，你也可以在不同的语境中使用它，也许不限于体育。
Okay.
好的。
So, maybe we can say, our company is ahead of all the others by a mile.
所以，也许我们可以说，我们公司遥遥领先于其他所有公司。
Right.
对。
Or if you tell somebody to guess your age and they say, oh, I think you are 42.
或者如果你让别人猜你的年龄，他们说，哦，我觉得你42岁。
Oh, you could say, you're off by a mile.
哦，你可以说，你差远了。
Right.
对。
So, you're really, really wrong.
所以，你错得很离谱。
Right.
对。
Exactly.
没错。
Yeah.
是的。
So, it's a way of exaggerating a little bit.
所以，这是一种稍微夸张的方式。
Yes.
是的。
And saying it's really obvious.
并且说这很明显。
Right.
对。
Well, three awesome phrases.
嗯，三个很棒的短语。
And I think it will help us to hear them one more time.
我觉得再听一遍会有帮助。
So, let's listen to the dialogue.
所以，我们来听一下对话。
Welcome back, soccer fans.
欢迎回来，球迷们。
My name is Rick Fields.
我是里克·菲尔兹。
And as always, I am joined by my commentating wingman, Bob Copeland.
和往常一样，我的解说搭档鲍勃·科普兰也在这里。
And we're in the brink of soccer history today as Ecuador and Brazil are tied 1-1 as we begin
今天我们正处在足球历史的边缘，厄瓜多尔和巴西以1-1战平，
the second half of the 2022 World Cup.
2022年世界杯下半场开始了。
The ref calls the players for the kickoff and here we go.
裁判召集球员准备开球，我们开始了。
Ecuador quickly passes the ball to the midfield.
厄瓜多尔迅速将球传到中场。
But oh, it's out of bounds.
但哦，球出界了。
That'll be a throw in for Brazil.
巴西将获得一个界外球。
Adriano has the ball and makes a long pass to Ruigno.
阿德里亚诺拿球，长传给鲁伊尼奥。
And the ref has called him offside.
裁判判他越位。
No question about it.
毫无疑问。
He was offside by a mile.
他越位了一大截。
We have a goal kick for Ecuador.
厄瓜多尔获得一个球门球。
Edison Mendes heads it to Valencia.
埃迪森·门德斯头球传给瓦伦西亚。
He shoots.
他射门了。
Deflected by the defender.
被后卫挡出。
And we have a corner kick.
我们获得一个角球。
Delgado takes the corner.
德尔加多主罚角球。
We have a foul.
犯规了。
Oh, no.
哦，不。
Dida, the goalkeeper, has fouled the Ecuadorian player.
门将迪达对厄瓜多尔球员犯规了。
He gets a yellow card and that will be a penalty kick.
他吃到一张黄牌，那将是一个点球。
This is the perfect opportunity for Ecuador to get ahead in this match and become world
这是厄瓜多尔在这场比赛中领先并成为世界冠军的绝佳机会。
champions.
冠军。
He gets ready for the kick.
他准备罚球。
He shoots and he...
他射门了，他……
Okay well, as you all may know, soccer is a very popular sport, especially in Latin
好的，正如大家可能知道的，足球是一项非常受欢迎的运动，尤其是在拉丁美洲。
America.
美洲。
That's right.
没错。
And your favorite team, Ecuador, are they really this good in soccer?
你最喜欢的球队厄瓜多尔，他们真的这么擅长足球吗？
Are they really going to win the 2022 Cup?
他们真的会赢得2022年世界杯吗？
Well, maybe not.
嗯，也许不会。
Well, actually Ecuador has improved with time, but usually it's the strong teams like Argentina
嗯，实际上厄瓜多尔随着时间的推移有所进步，但通常是像阿根廷和巴西这样的强队主导这个地区，对吧？
and Brazil who dominate the region, right?
巴西主导这个地区，对吧？
Right.
对。
But yeah, hopefully we'll make it next time.
但是的，希望我们下次能成功。
Okay, well, I have my money on Ecuador.
好的，嗯，我把赌注押在厄瓜多尔上。
For 2022.
为了2022年。
But yeah, not on Canada.
但是的，不是加拿大。
There's no hope for us.
我们没希望了。
Well, Canada is doing really well now.
嗯，加拿大现在表现很好。
They actually beat Mexico, if I'm not mistaken.
如果我没记错的话，他们实际上击败了墨西哥。
Oh, actually that's sort of...
哦，那有点……
Yeah, I kind of remember that now.
是的，我现在有点印象了。
But I think there's no hope for us to beat Brazil or Argentina, one of these big countries.
但我认为我们没希望击败巴西或阿根廷这些大国之一。
We have the next World Cup coming up, so it's really exciting and I don't know who's going
下一届世界杯就要来了，这真的很令人兴奋，我不知道谁会赢。
to win.
赢。
All right.
好的。
Well, listeners, who do you think is going to win?
嗯，听众们，你们觉得谁会赢？
Who is the best soccer team out there?
哪支足球队是最好的？
Right.
对。
There are really good soccer teams, although some countries aren't really known for their
确实有很好的足球队，尽管有些国家并不以足球闻名，比如俄罗斯。
soccer, like Russia.
俄罗斯。
You don't really hear too much soccer from Russia.
你不太听到俄罗斯的足球消息。
Really?
真的吗？
Or from China is for that.
或者中国也是。
I wonder how popular it is in these countries.
我想知道足球在这些国家有多受欢迎。
So let us know.
所以请告诉我们。
Come to our website, EnglishPod.com.
来我们的网站，EnglishPod.com。
Tell us how popular soccer is in your country or what team you are a fan of.
告诉我们足球在你的国家有多受欢迎，或者你是哪支球队的粉丝。
I know many people like the European Cups and they're fans of Barcelona or the Italian
我知道很多人喜欢欧洲杯，他们是巴塞罗那或意大利球队的粉丝。
teams.
意大利球队。
Well, come to the website.
嗯，来网站吧。
Marco and I are always around to answer your questions.
马可和我随时都在回答你们的问题。
And until next time, goodbye.
下次再见，再见。
Goodbye.
再见。